<?xml version="1.0"?>
 <rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ATL News</title>
    <link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/</link>
    <description>ATL News</description>
    <item>
		<title>ATL 3.0.0 has been released</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/modeling/m2m/downloads/?project=atl#R200906220943</link>
		<description>
			ATL 3.0.0 has just been released, and introduce a lot of improvements at both UI and API level. Consult the <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/ATL_3.0.0_New_and_Noteworthy">News and Noteworthy page</a> for more details.
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 16:30:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New use case available: UML2 activity diagrams to AnyLogic simulation models</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/UML2AnyLogic/</link>
		<description>
			This use case presents a transformation from annotated UML2 activity diagrams to AnyLogic simulation models.
		</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 17:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New use case available: Rational Rose to UML2 Tools</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MDL2GMF/</link>
		<description>
			This use case shows how we can reuse UML projects created with Rational Rose and import them in GMF (specifically in UML2 Tools) using ATL transformations. In this use case, we 
			only support UML class diagrams. In practice, this use case was applied to the QVT metamodel available on the OMG site.
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 16:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New use case available: Visual Representation for Code Clone Tools</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/VisualRepCodeClone/</link>
		<description>
			The aim of this use case is to realize a uniform visual representation for different code clone detection tools. 
			Different analysis results provided by different code clone detection tools can be injected into models. These models will be transformed to a generic Code Clone DSL model,
			and then into SVG model. Finally, the SVG code can be automatically extracted from SVG model.
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2007 14:25:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL Transformation Scenario: UML Class Diagram to UML Profile</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#UMLCD2UMLProfile</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This ATL scenario transforms a UML2 Class Diagram into a UML2 Profile.</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 16:45:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New use case available : Modeling Web applications</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/webapp.modeling/</link>
		<description>
			This use case shows how model weaving is used to help in the development of model transformations. In some cases, the gap between the input and output metamodels makes it 
			difficult to develop a model transformation that works for every input model. In such cases a weaving model can be used to enrich the input model by annotation. This process 
			can be thought of as a way to parameterize the model transformation.
		</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 5 Oct 2007 16:50:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL Transformation Scenario: KM3 metamodel to ATL comparison transformation</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#KM32CONFATL</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This package include a higher-order transformation (HOT) that takes a KM3 metamodel as source model and generates a model of an ATL
				transformation. This transformation takes two source models (an	implementation and an architecture model) that conform to that
				metamodel and generates a target model that is the union of the two	source models with each of the model elements labelled convergent,
				divergent or absent depending on their occurrence in one or both of	the architecture and implementation models.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The HOT makes it possible to generically compare models conforming to metamodels that describe architectural module views. The HOT accepts
				source models that are injected KM3 models. They should define four abstract elements, namely ViewElement, and its specialisations:
				ViewEntity, ViewRelation, and ViewRoot. The rest of the metamodel should extend these generic elements, for instance, a Module element
				would extend a ViewEntity, while a Uses element would extend a ViewRelation.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The HOT generates appropriate transformation rules and helpers for all elements in the KM3 source model. The generated helpers for
				determining whether an element in the implementation model correspond to an element in the architecture model (isMapping) do this based on
				naming for ViewEntity elements. For ViewRelation elements correspondence is determined by checking whether the source and the
				target of the ViewRelation are mappings of each other.
			</p>
			<p>This scenario is contributed by Bas Graaf (SERG - Software Engineering Research Group, Delft University of Technology).</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 17:30:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>Update of ATL scenarios of the Models Measurement Use Case</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#ModelMeasurement</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			The 8 scenarios of <b>Model Measurement Use Case</b> have been updated. This set of scenarios shows how to compute and generate measures on KM3 metamodels or UML2 models, and how to display them in different way
			</p>
			<ul>
				Scenarios list:
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#ModelMeasurement">Model (KM3 and UML2) Measurement</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#KM32Measure">KM3 to Measure</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Measure2Table">Measure to Table</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Measure2XHTML">Measure to XHTML</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Table2SVGBarChart">Table to SVGBarChart</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Table2SVGBarChart">Table to SVGPieChart</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Table2TabularHTML">Table to TabularHTML</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#UML22Measure">UML2 to Measure</a></li>
			</ul>
			<p>These scenarios are contributed by Eric Vepa (<a href="http://www.sodius.com">SODIUS</a>).</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2007 18:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL Transformation Scenario: Measure to XHTML</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Measure2XHTML</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				The Measure to XHTML example describes a transformation from a Measure model to a XHTML file representing the 
				measurement data.
			</p>
			<p>This scenario is contributed by Eric Vepa (<a href="http://www.sodius.com">SODIUS</a>).</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2007 17:30:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>ATL 2.0.0RC2 is available</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/download</link>
		<description>
			<p>
				ATL 2.0.0RC2 is available. The preferred way of installing is via the Update Manager.
				More details available here : <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/download/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/download/</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
				Additionally, two <b>ATL Ready-To-Use</b> bundles are available:
				<ul>
					<li>ATL Bundle 2.0 Standard Version, <i>including Eclipse 3.3, EMF 2.3, ATL 2.0.0RC2, and ATL basic examples</i>.</li>
					<li>ATL Bundle 2.0 UML2 Version, <i>including Eclipse 3.3, EMF 2.3, UML 2.1, ATL 2.0.0RC2, UML2 Driver for ATL, and ATL basic examples</i>.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				ATL release notes are published here: <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/ATL_ReleaseNotes">http://wiki.eclipse.org/ATL_ReleaseNotes</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2007 00:15:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL Transformation Scenario: WSDL to R2ML</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#WSDL2R2ML</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				The WSDL to R2ML transformation scenario describes a transformation from WSDL (Web Services Description Language) 
				metamodel into a R2ML (REWERSE I1 Markup Language) metamodel. "WSDL enables one to separate the description of the abstract 
				functionality offered by a service from concrete details of a service description such as 'how' and 'where' that
				functionality is offered". REWERSE I1 Rule Markup Language is a general web rule markup language, that can represent
				different rule types: integrity, reaction, derivation and production. It is used as pivotal metamodel to enable sharing
				rules between different rule languages.
			</p>
			<p>
				This scenario is a contribution from Marko Ribaric.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 July 2007 16:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Models Measurement</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/ModelsMeasurement/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This use case shows how to compute and generate measures on KM3 metamodels or UML2 models, and how to display them in different way (HTML, and SVG).
				This work has been done in collaboration between <a href="http://www.sodius.com">SODIUS</a> and the 
				<a href="http://www.sciences.univ-nantes.fr/lina/atl/">ATLAS Group</a>.	As a complementary application to this contribution, an online service is provided at SODIUS's web site under the name "MC-Meter".
				The online measurement service is available at: <a href="http://www.mdworkbench.com/measuring.php">http://www.mdworkbench.com/measuring.php</a>
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/ModelsMeasurement/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/ModelsMeasurement/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 July 2007 15:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>7 new and updated scenarios related to model measurement are available</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#ModelMeasurement</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			7 new and updated scenarios are available. This set of scenarios shows how to compute and generate measures on KM3 metamodels or UML2 models, and how to display them in different way
			</p>
			<ul>
				Scenarios list:
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#ModelMeasurement">Model (KM3 and UML2) Measurement</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#KM32Measure">KM3 to Measure</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Measure2Table">Measure to Table</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Table2SVGBarChart">Table to SVGBarChart</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Table2SVGBarChart">Table to SVGPieChart</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#Table2TabularHTML">Table to TabularHTML</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#UML22Measure">UML2 to Measure</a></li>
			</ul>
			<p>These scenarios are contributed by Eric Vepa (<a href="http://www.sodius.com">SODIUS</a>).</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 July 2007 12:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>July 13th, 2007 - Free tutorial - "Practice of model transformation and model weaving with ATL and AMW"</title>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				The INRIA ATLAS team organizes in Nantes (France) a day essentially dedicated to the practice of model transformation (ATL) and model weaving (AMW) tools. This day is intended for 
				ATL and AMW beginners who want to improve their knowledge in the domain. The tools are available in open source under Eclipse and a previous minimal experience with ATL is 
				recommended.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The participation to this day is free of charge but the inscription is mandatory. The number of available places being limited (~15), the inscription's requests will be 
				treated depending on their arrival order.
			</p>

			<p align="justify">
				The tutorial takes place the 13th of July 2007, from 9h to 12h and from 14h to 18h. The inscription's requests have to be sent as soon as possible to Hugo Bruneliere
				(Hugo DOT Bruneliere AT univ-nantes DOT fr).
			</p>

			<p align="justify">
				Please provide us in your request the basic information such as your name, company, phone number, etc. According to the number of available places, an answer will be sent 
				to you including more details concerning the course of the day.
			</p>

			<p align="justify">
				The tutorials will be either in French or in English, depending on the audience. All the slides will be in English and will be provided to the participants at the 
				beginning of the day (slides non-available outside of the tutorial).
			</p>

			<p align="justify">
				The goal of this day is to provide a practical point of view on Model-Driven Engineering (MDE). By following numerous examples and use cases, you will discover how to:
				<ul>
					<li>Refine models in order to target a specific execution platform;</li>
					<li>Make tools and norms interoperable;</li>
					<li>Build, at low cost, domain-specific languages (DSLs);</li>
					<li>Define chains of transformations and integrate them in a workflow.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>

			<p align="justify">
				Each of these points will use on or several tools of the Atlas Model Management Architecture (AMMA) tool suite, with in particular:
				<ul>
					<li>Atlas Transformation Language (ATL): a model transformation language and engine;</li>
					<li>Kernel MetaMetaModel (KM3): a metamodel definition language;</li>
					<li>Atlas Model Weaver (AMW): a model weaving prototype for interoperability and traceability;</li>
					<li>Textual Concrete Syntax (TCS): a model textual syntaxes definition language;</li>
					<li>Atlas MegaModel Management (AM3): a modeling artifact management prototype in order to facilitate the model-driven development (collaboration, distribution, etc).</li>
				</ul>
			</p>

			<p align="justify">
				All these tools are available from the Eclipse foundation website (http://www.eclipse.org ). ATL is a component of the model-to-model transformation project (M2M).The others 
				are available as components of the GMT project. GMT has the goal to provide an incubation area for innovative projects related to model engineering. M2M and GMT are parts of 
				the top-level modeling project gathering the model engineering activities of the Eclipse foundation.
			</p>

			<p align="justify">
				Reference: 
				<ul>
					<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/</a></li>
					<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/amw/">http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/amw/</a></li>
					<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/am3/">http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/am3/</a></li>
					<li><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/tcs/">http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/tcs/</a></li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 5 July 2007 12:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL Transformation Scenario: OpenBlueLab to UML</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#OBL2UML</link>
		<description>
			<p>
			<a href="http://www.openbluelab.org">OpenBlueLab</a> project's ambition is to provide an application which you can adapt easily by just updating UML models 
			contained in the <a href="http://www.openbluelab.org">OpenBlueLab</a> download,  without writing any line of code. <a href="http://www.openbluelab.org">OpenBlueLab</a>
			use as input XMI file but too OBL file conforms to our specialized metamodel used to generate a particular editor,  <a href="http://forge.openbluelab.org/gf/project/omf/">OpenBlueLab Developer Studio</a>.
			So we have made a transformation which permit to get XMI file conforms to the metamodel UML from OBL file if we want to re-integrate OBL models in UML  modeler.
			</p>
			<p>This scenario is a contribution from Benjamin Chevallereau (<a href="http://www.openbluelab.org">OpenBlueLab</a>).</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 8 June 2007 21:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: RSM to Topcased UML2 Editor</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/RSM2Topcased/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				TOPCASED currently uses on the ATL model transformation toolkit. Model transformations have been mainly used in order to access models defined using other editors than TOPCASED 
				one's. This use case presents an operational application of ATL to bridge RSM and TOPCASED.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/RSM2Topcased/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/RSM2Topcased/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 8 June 2007 10:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Verifying UML profiled models</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/Verifying_UML_profiled_models/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This use case shows how to use and integrate a model transformation service in a UML Modeler to verify a UML profiled model.
				The used UML Modeler is <a href="http://www.papyrusuml.org/">Papyrus</a> (<a href="http://www-list.cea.fr/">CEA LIST</a>).
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/Verifying_UML_profiled_models/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/Verifying_UML_profiled_models/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 7 June 2007 10:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: QVT to ATL Virtual Machine Compiler</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/QVT2ATLVM/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This work provides a QVT compiler that targets the ATL Virtual Machine (ATL VM), and thus provides executability of QVT programs on top of the ATL VM. The code generator is written 
				in the ACG (Atl Code Generation) Domain-Specific Language (DSL). It takes as input a QVT model (typically in XMI format) that may have been created by a QVT front-end (i.e., a parser 
				and type checker) like Eclipse/modeling/m2m/Procedural QVT, or SmartQVT. The output of the code generator is a ".asm" file similar to the ones generated by the ATL compiler, or the 
				ACG compiler (both also written in ACG).
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/QVT2ATLVM/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/QVT2ATLVM/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 6 June 2007 18:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Measuring UML models</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/Measuring_UML_models/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This use case shows how to use and integrate a model transformation service in a UML Modeler to compute and generate quality measures on UML models.
				The used UML Modeler is <a href="http://www.papyrusuml.org/">Papyrus</a> (<a href="http://www-list.cea.fr/">CEA LIST</a>).
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/Measuring_UML_models/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/Measuring_UML_models/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 0:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Using a UML modeler to generate metamodels</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/UML2MOF/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This use case shows how to use and integrate a model transformation service in a UML Modeler to generate metamodels conforming to KM3, MOF 1.4, and Ecore.
				The used UML Modeler is <a href="http://www.papyrusuml.org/">Papyrus</a> (<a href="http://www-list.cea.fr/">CEA LIST</a>).
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/UML2MOF/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/UML2MOF/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2007 2:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: A Metamodel Independent Approach to Difference Representation</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MMIndApproachtoDiffRep/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This work presents an ATL implementation of a metamodel independent approach to the representation of model differences which is agnostic of
				the calculation method. Given two models being differenced which conform to a metamodel, their difference is conforming to another metamodel
				derived from the former by an automated transformation. Interestingly, difference models are first-class artifacts which in turn induce other
				transformations, such that they can be applied to one of the differenced models to automatically obtain the other one.
				This work has been done by <a href="http://www.di.univaq.it/~cicchetti">Antonio Cicchetti</a>,
				<a href="http://www.di.univaq.it/~diruscio">Davide Di Ruscio</a> and
				<a href="http://www.di.univaq.it/~alfonso">Alfonso Pierantonio</a> (Universit&#224; dell'Aquila).
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MMIndApproachtoDiffRep/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MMIndApproachtoDiffRep/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 6 Apr 2007 16:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Sharing Rules Between OCL/UML and SWRL/OWL</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SharingRulesBetweenOCLUML_SWRLOWL/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
		    	This work presents an implementation of sharing rules between two rule languages from different domains: OCL (Object Constraint Language) together with UML and SWRL 
		    	(Semantic Web Rule Language) together with OWL. For this integration we used the R2ML (REWERSE I1 Rule Markup Language) metamodel as pivotal metamodel. The R2ML is a 
		    	general Web rule markup language and it can represent different rule types: integrity, reaction, derivation and production. This work has been done by 
		    	<a href="http://milan.milanovic.org">Milan Milanovic</a> in collaboration 
		    	between the <a href="http://goodoldai.org.yu/">GOOD OLD AI Laboratory</a> at <a href="http://www.bg.ac.yu">University of Belgrade</a>,
		    	<a href="http://www.sfu.ca/siat" target="_self">School of Interactive Arts and Technology</a> at 
		    	<a href="http://www.surrey.sfu.ca" target="_self">Simon Fraser University Surrey</a> in Canada and 
		    	<a href="http://oxygen.informatik.tu-cottbus.de/IT/">Chair of Internet Technology</a> at 
		    	<a href="http://www.tu-cottbus.de/">Brandenburg University of Technology at Cottbus</a> in Germany.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SharingRulesBetweenOCLUML_SWRLOWL/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SharingRulesBetweenOCLUML_SWRLOWL/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2007 18:10:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL scenario: OCL to SWRL</title> 
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#OCL2SWRL</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			The OCL to SWRL transformation scenario describes a transformation from OCL (Object Constraint Language) 
			metamodel (with EMOF metamodel) into a R2ML (REWERSE I1 Rule Markup Language) metamodel and then to the
			SWRL (Semantic Web Rule Language) metamodel (RDM) with ODM (OWL language metamodel). The Object Constraint Language (OCL) 
			is a language that enables one to describe expressions and constraints on object-oriented (UML and MOF) models and other 
			object modeling artifacts. An expression is an indication or specification of a value. A constraint is a restriction on one 
			or more values of (part of) an object-oriented model or system. REWERSE I1 Rule Markup Language (R2ML) is a 
			general web rule markup language, that can represent different rule types: integrity, reaction, derivation 
			and production. It is used as pivotal metamodel to enable sharing rules between different rule languages, in this
			case with the OCL. SWRL is a web rule language based on combination of the OWL DL and OWL Lite sublanguages of the
			OWL Web Ontology Language, with the Unary/Binary Datalog RuleML sublanguages of the Rule Markup Language (RuleML).
			</p>
			<p>This scenario is a contribution from <a href="http://milan.milanovic.org/">Milan Milanovic</a>.</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2007 11:30:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>Documentation of the AMMA/ATL Ant Tasks available</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/doc/ANT_Task_AMMA.pdf</link>
		<description>
			<p>
				A presentation of the AMMA/ATL Ant Tasks is available here: 
				<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/doc/ANT_Task_AMMA.pdf">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/doc/ANT_Task_AMMA.pdf</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
				A wiki page is also available: <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/index.php/AM3_Ant_Tasks">http://wiki.eclipse.org/index.php/AM3_Ant_Tasks</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2007 11:40:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>A new development build of ATL is available</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/download/</link>
		<description>
			<p>
				A <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/download/">new development build</a> of ATL is available.
				This version contains ATL and AM3 (with additional libs).
			</p>
			<p>
				A complete bundle containing Eclipse, EMF, ATL and AM3 (with additional libs) is also available
				<a href="http://www.sciences.univ-nantes.fr/lina/atl/www/atldemo/ATLBundle_20070217.zip">here</a>.
				This bundle is ready to use with 4 ATL scenarios and the user guides.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 14:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Implementing two business rule languages: PRR and IRL</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/PRR2IRL/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This work presents a case study of implementing two business rule languages: Production Rule Representation (PRR) and ILOG Rule Language (IRL). We show how a pivot 
				language can be translated into a concrete one with the help of model engineering. The outcome of this experiment also provides an interesting example of DSLs coordination. 
				This work has been done in collaboration between the <a href="http://www.sciences.univ-nantes.fr/lina/atl/">ATLAS Group</a> in Nantes and <a href="http://www.ilog.com/">ILOG</a>.
				A <b>web service PRR to IRL</b> is available here: <a href="http://www.sciences.univ-nantes.fr/lina/atl/atldemo/prronline/">http://www.sciences.univ-nantes.fr/lina/atl/atldemo/prronline/</a>.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/PRR2IRL/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/PRR2IRL/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 11:50:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: From Hoare's Monitors to Dijkstra's Semaphores</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MonitorToSemaphore/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This is a classic in synchronization. We propose an automatic translation from Hoare's monitors as defined in <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MonitorToSemaphore/#ref1">[1]</a> into Dijkstra's semaphores as 
				initially introduced in <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MonitorToSemaphore/#ref2">[2]</a>.
				The ATL transformation code follows the rules given in <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MonitorToSemaphore/#ref1">[1]</a>. A complete reprint of this paper is available at: 
				<a href="http://www.acm.org/classics/feb96/">http://www.acm.org/classics/feb96/</a>.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MonitorToSemaphore/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/MonitorToSemaphore/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 11:50:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: From UML Activity Diagram to Project Management Software</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/UML2MsProject/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This use case shows the possibility to have interoperability between an UML activity diagram and a project management software like MsProject.
				UML Activity Diagrams are typically used for business process modeling, for modeling the logic captured by a single use case or usage scenario, or for modeling the 
				detailed logic of a business rule. Microsoft Project is a project management software program developed by Microsoft.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/UML2MsProject/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/UML2MsProject/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 11:50:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL scenario: OCL to R2ML</title> 
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#OCL2R2ML</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			The OCL to R2ML transformation scenario describes a transformation from OCL (Object Constraint Language) metamodel (with EMOF metamodel) into a R2ML (REWERSE I1 Rule Markup 
			Language) metamodel. The Object Constraint Language (OCL) is a language that enables one to describe expressions and constraints on object-oriented (UML and MOF) models and 
			other object modeling artifacts. An expression is an indication or specification of a value. A constraint is a restriction on one or more values of (part of) an object-oriented 
			model or system. REWERSE I1 Rule Markup Language (R2ML) is a general web rule markup language, that can represent different rule types: integrity, reaction, derivation and production. 
			It is used as pivotal metamodel to enable sharing rules between different rule languages, in this case with the OCL.
			</p>
			<p>This scenario is a contribution from <a href="http://milan.milanovic.org/">Milan Milanovic</a>.</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 17:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL scenario: R2ML to OCL</title> 
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#R2ML2OCL</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			The R2ML to OCL transformation scenario describes a transformation from R2ML (REWERSE I1 Rule Markup Language) metamodel into a OCL (Object Constraint Language) metamodel (with EMOF 
			metamodel). The Object Constraint Language (OCL) is a language that enables one to describe expressions and constraints on object-oriented (UML and MOF) models and other object modeling 
			artifacts. An expression is an indication or specification of a value. A constraint is a restriction on one or more values of (part of) an object-oriented model or system. REWERSE I1 Rule 
			Markup Language (R2ML) is a general web rule markup language, that can represent different rule types: integrity, reaction, derivation and production. It is used as pivotal metamodel to 
			enable sharing rules between different rule languages, in this case with the OCL.
			</p>
			<p>This scenario is a contribution from <a href="http://milan.milanovic.org/">Milan Milanovic</a>.</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 17:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>New ATL scenario: R2ML to SWRL</title> 
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#R2ML2SWRL</link> 
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			The R2ML to SWRL transformation scenario describes a transformation from R2ML (REWERSE I1 Markup Language) metamodel into a SWRL (Semantic Web Rule Language) metamodel (RDM). SWRL is a 
			web rule language based on combination of the OWL DL and OWL Lite sublanguages of the OWL Web Ontology Language, with the Unary/Binary Datalog RuleML sublanguages of the Rule Markup 
			Language (RuleML). REWERSE I1 Rule Markup Language is a general web rule markup language, that can represent different rule types: integrity, reaction, derivation and production. It 
			is used as pivotal metamodel to enable sharing rules between different rule languages, in this case with the SWRL.
			</p>
			<p>This scenario is a contribution from <a href="http://milan.milanovic.org/">Milan Milanovic</a>.</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 17:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL scenario: SWRL to R2ML</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#SWRL2R2ML</link> 
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			The SWRL to R2ML transformation scenario describes a transformation from SWRL (Semantic Web Rule Language) metamodel (RDM) into a R2ML (REWERSE I1 Markup Language) metamodel. SWRL is 
			a web rule language based on combination of the OWL DL and OWL Lite sublanguages of the OWL Web Ontology Language, with the Unary/Binary Datalog RuleML sublanguages of the Rule Markup 
			Language (RuleML). REWERSE I1 Rule Markup Language is a general web rule markup language, that can represent different rule types: integrity, reaction, derivation and production. It is 
			used as pivotal metamodel to enable sharing rules between different rule languages, in this case with the SWRL.
			</p>
			<p>This scenario is a contribution from <a href="http://milan.milanovic.org/">Milan Milanovic</a>.</p>
		</description> 
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 17:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL scenario: KM3 to OWL</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#KM32OWL</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				This ATL scenario shows up a traduction of KM3 into OWL (Web Ontology language) ontology language. 
				This scenario is composed of one transformation (KM32OWL) and an OWL extractor that produces XML 
				documents conform to the OWL syntax defined by the W3C. Resulting ontology can be used into ontology 
				development tools like Protege <a href="http://protege.stanford.edu">(see http://protege.stanford.edu)</a>.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				This scenario is used to auto-generate the <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/am3/zoos/atlanticOWLZoo/">Atlantic OWL mirror zoo</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 17:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL scenario: KM3 to XML</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/#KM32XML</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				The KM3 to XML scenario expresses each metamodel written in KM3 textual syntax with a default 
				XML syntax. As a default syntax, it is not the more concise but it is non-ambiguous and can be apply 
				to any KM3 model.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				This scenario is used to auto-generate the <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/am3/zoos/atlanticXMLZoo/">Atlantic XML mirror zoo</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 16:50:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Web Syndication Interoperability (RSS and Atom)</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/WebSyndicationInteroperability/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			People who generate web syndication feeds have a choice of formats. Today, the two most likely candidates are RSS 2.0 and Atom 1.0.
			The goal of this case study is to provide a bridge between both formats by using a light and flexible interoperability solution.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/WebSyndicationInteroperability/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/WebSyndicationInteroperability/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2007 14:50:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Models Validation through Petri nets</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SimplePDL2Tina/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			This work presents a use case of model transformation using ATL rules to validate MDD's models.
			This use case considers a simplified process description language, SimplePDL. It then presents a property-driven approach
			in which SimplePDL process models are translated into Petri nets. SimplePDL behavioral properties 
			are expressed on corresponding Petri nets in LTL (<i>Linear Temporal Logic</i>).
			The Tina toolkit and, in particular, its model-checker, are used to validate process models by checking the expressed properties.
			This use case has been done by <a href="http://combemale.perso.enseeiht.fr/">Benoit Combemale</a> (<a href="http://www.irit.fr">IRIT</a>). This is a collaboration between 
			<a href="http://www.irit.fr">IRIT</a> and <a href="http://www.laas.fr/">LAAS</a> labs in Toulouse, France.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SimplePDL2Tina/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SimplePDL2Tina/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2007 14:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

    <item>
		<title>New ATL documentation: Presentation of the ATL Virtual Machine</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/doc/ATL_VM_Presentation_[1.0].pdf</link>
		<description>
			This <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/doc/ATL_VM_Presentation_[1.0].pdf">presentation</a> gives an introduction to the ATL Virtual Machine.
			It is available in the <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/doc/">ATL doc</a> section.
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 16:40:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Software Build Tools Interoperability (Make, Ant, Maven)</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/BridgeBetweenBuildTools/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				Make is one of the most common build tool. It remains widely used but essentially in Unix-based 
				platforms. Many problems have surfaced with scaling make to work with modern, large software 
				projects. So, it is interesting to provide some bridges from Make to other build tools like Ant 
				(which is popular for Java development and uses an XML file format) and Maven (a Java tool for 
				management project and automated software build).
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/BridgeBetweenBuildTools/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/BridgeBetweenBuildTools/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 11:35:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL use case: Software Quality Control Tools Interoperability (Bugzilla, Mantis, Excel)</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SoftwareQualityControlToolsInteroperability/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				Problems of tools interoperability can be found in various domains. Software quality control is one 
				of these. This use case presents an implementation of bridges between different bug tracking tools 
				like Bugzilla, and Mantis. We also consider that bug tracking information may be handled in a 
				generic tool like Excel.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SoftwareQualityControlToolsInteroperability/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/SoftwareQualityControlToolsInteroperability/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 11:30:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL transformation scenario is available: Verification of SimplePDL models through PetriNet and Tina tools</title>
		<link>http://www.eclipse.org/gmt/atl/atlTransformations/#SimplePDL2Tina</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
			   	These transformations are part of a <a href="http://www.combemale.fr/wiki/doku.php?id=private:enseignement:metamodeling">Course</a> (in french)
 				about metamodeling, models transformation and verification. 
				These transformations introduce a property-driven approach to validate models through a translational semantics to Petri nets.
			</p>

			<p align="justify">This contribution was made by <a href="http://combemale.perso.enseeiht.fr/" >Benoit Combemale</a>.</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2006 16:55:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL use case: DSLs coordination for Telephony</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/DSLsTelephony/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				A new ATL use case is available: DSLs coordination for Telephony. This work presents a case study of implementing two telephony languages: SPL and CPL.
				They are partially based on similar vocabularies. However they are very different and have been designed to be used by different people.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				The use case is available at: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/DSLsTelephony/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/DSLsTelephony/</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 1 Feb 2007 11:45:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>Creation of a section "ATL Use Cases"</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/</link>
		<description>
			<p align="justify">
				A section "ATL Use Cases" has been opened. The use cases will be updated regularly with improved description, new documentation, and implementation.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				Do not hesitate to post messages on the M2M newsgroup (<a href="news://news.eclipse.org/eclipse.modeling.m2m">eclipse.modeling.m2m</a>) if you have any particular interests 
				and/or questions about any of the presented use cases.
				Contributions from the community of new use cases will be welcome. We are also always interested by new ideas and proposals of possible other use cases.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				See <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/usecases/</a> for consulting the use cases list.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 1 Feb 2007 11:45:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>The archives from the ATL Yahoo Group are available</title>
      	<link>http://www.sciences.univ-nantes.fr/lina/atl/www/atl_discussion_archive/</link>
		<description>			
			<a name="newsATL_20070129_A" />
			<p align="justify">
				The <a href="http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/atl_discussion/">old ATL discussion group</a> is now closed. The archives are available
				<a href="http://www.sciences.univ-nantes.fr/lina/atl/www/atl_discussion_archive/">here</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 11:45:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>New ATL example presentation: "Families to Persons"</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/news/#newsATL_20070116_A</link>
		<description>
			<a name="newsATL_20070116_A" />
			<p align="justify">
				A new ATL Use Case "Families to Persons" has been created. It is available in <a href="../doc/ATLUseCase_Families2Persons.pdf">PDF</a> and 
				<a href="../doc/ATLUseCase_Families2Persons.ppt">Powerpoint</a> formats.
				This presentation describes a very simple model transformation example, some kind of ATL "hello world". This is not a recommendation on how to program in ATL, just an initial example.
				Other presentations and exercise questions that could be based on this example will be created. Please, do not hesitate to provide some feedbacks on this presentation or to contribute.
				The source code is available in the ATL transformations zoo: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/atlTransformations/Families2Persons/Families2Persons.zip">Families2Persons.zip</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 11:30:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>ATL web site moved from GMT to M2M</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/news/#newsATL_20070115_C</link>
		<description>			
			<a name="newsATL_20070115_C" />
			<p align="justify">
				ATL web site moved from GMT to M2M. And it is now accessible here: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/</a>.
			</p>
			<p align="justify">
				As a consequence, the old ATL mailing list migrated to the <a href="news://news.eclipse.org/eclipse.modeling.m2m">Eclipse M2M newsgroup</a>.
				For information about accessing Eclipse newsgroups, see: <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/newsgroups/">http://www.eclipse.org/newsgroups/</a>.
				Last point, for the Eclipse M2M posting. Since we are going to share this newsgroup with the
				other M2M components, the PMC has asked us to prefix all posts (questions, answers, comments), with the component name.
				You will need to add [ATL] at the beginning of the subject of your post o that they may be distinguished from the posts related to the other components.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 17:30:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

   <item>
		<title>ATL recognized as a standard solution for model transformation in Eclipse</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/news/#newsATL_20070115_B</link>
		<description>
			<a name="newsATL_20070115_B" />
			
			<p align="justify">The ATL transformation language defined by INRIA has been recognized as a standard component in Eclipse. ATL is now integrated into the new M2M (Model-to-Model, 
			<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/">http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/</a>) project. This project belongs to the Eclipse modeling activities branch 
			(Eclipse Modeling, <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/modeling/">http://www.eclipse.org/modeling/</a>).</p>

			<p align="justify">Together with the Borland and Compuware solutions, ATL will now be part of the set of Eclipse recommended tools for performing model-to-model transformations. ATL allows to implement 
			some simple UML-to-Java conversions but also much more complex transformations, for instance in the context of heterogeneous data or modernization of legacy systems.</p>

			<p align="justify">The integration of ATL into this new M2M project is an important recognition. ATL will be used in the same way as other Eclipse standard solutions such as EMF, Ecore or GMF. Moreover, 
			the support of the Eclipse foundation developers' community will ensure to ATL an important additional help for development and will also offer good stability in time to language users. 
			Some companies did not wait this for integrating ATL into their own toolset or even into their commercial offers (ATL is released under the EPL license).</p>

			<p align="justify">ATL is being used in the ModelPlex European project. It is also an official selected solution in the <a href="http://www.usine-logicielle.org/">"Usine Logicielle" project</a> of the "System@tic" Paris cluster 
			(<a href="http://www.systematic-paris-region.org/">http://www.systematic-paris-region.org/</a>) or in the French OpenEmbeDD project. More than one hundred industrial and academic sites are using ATL in many countries (France, Germany, Italy, 
			Spain, USA, Canada, Brazil, etc). In France the TopCased project of the Aerospace valley cluster (<a href="http://www.topcased.org/">http://www.topcased.org/</a>) also uses the ATL solution. Many university centers, such as the 
			"Ecole Centrale de Lille", are using ATL as a basis for teaching MDA approaches.</p>

			<p align="justify">In 2004 the ATL initiative already won an award for the "IBM Eclipse Innovation Grants". Since this date, the language has evolved in three successive versions, with now an advanced 
			development environment, a stable virtual machine, a significant transformations' library and an important users and contributors community. The language has been designed and developed at 
			INRIA Nantes by Frederic Jouault who is now the Eclipse M2M project leader. One of his main tasks will be to synchronize the efforts on the future ATL developments with the Compuware and 
			Borland components, which are more aligned on the QVT recommendation for model transformation as defined by the OMG.</p>

			<p align="justify">The recognition of the ATL language into the Eclipse modeling project is a very significant example of the current success of open-source approaches. In four years, an innovative 
			product, coming from basic research and supported by various initiatives such as the ModelWare Integrated European project has evolved from the status of laboratory prototype to the 
			level of stable industrial solution.</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 17:00:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>GMT/ATL 2004-2006 news have been archived</title>
      	<link>http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/news/newsArchived2006.php</link>
		<description>			
			<a name="newsATL_20070115_A" />
			<p align="justify">
				GMT/ATL 2004-2006 news moved to the archive news section. News from 2004 to 2006 are now available here:
				<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/m2m/atl/news/newsArchived2006.php">Archive 2004-2006</a>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 17:30:00 CET</pubDate>
	</item>

  </channel>
</rss>