<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan"
	xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="ATL">
	<release projectid="modeling.m2m.atl" version="3.2" />
	<introduction>
		<html:div>This document lays out the feature and API set for the
			3.2 release of the ATL project, of the Eclipse M2M Project.
		</html:div>
	</introduction>
	<release_deliverables>
		<html:p>
			The release deliverables have the same form as is found in most
			Eclipse projects, namely:
			<html:ul>
				<html:li>ATL source code release, available as versions tagged
					"R3_2" in the project's CVS repository.</html:li>
				<html:li>M2M ATL SDK (includes runtime and tooling components,
					with sources and documentation) (downloadable and update site).
				</html:li>
				<html:li>M2M ATL runtime binary distribution (downloadable and
					update site).</html:li>
				<html:li>M2M ATL examples (downloadable and update site).
				</html:li>
				<html:li>M2T ATL tests (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
			</html:ul>
		</html:p>
	</release_deliverables>
   <release_milestones>
      <preamble>
         <html:div>
Release milestones occur at roughly 6 week intervals 
and follow the Platform release milestone by the Indigo-established +2 delta interval.
The final ATL 3.2 release will available simultaneously 
with the 3.7 release of the Platform and all the other Helios projects.
         </html:div>
      </preamble>
<milestone date="09/28/2010" milestone="M2"></milestone>
<milestone date="11/09/2010" milestone="M3"></milestone>
<milestone date="12/14/2010" milestone="M4"></milestone>
<milestone date="02/01/2011" milestone="M5"></milestone>
<milestone date="03/15/2011" milestone="M6"><html:div>API freeze</html:div></milestone>
<milestone date="05/03/2011" milestone="M7"><html:div>Feature Freeze</html:div></milestone>
<milestone date="05/17/2011" milestone="RC1"></milestone>
<milestone date="05/24/2011" milestone="RC2"></milestone>
<milestone date="05/31/2011" milestone="RC3"></milestone>
<milestone date="06/07/2011" milestone="RC4"></milestone>
<milestone date="06/22/2011" milestone="Final"></milestone>
      <postamble>
        <html:div>
ATL will produce maintenance releases to align with the Helios Service Releases
which includes the Eclipse Platform's 3.6.1 and 3.6.2 releases.
ATL may produce additional interim maintenance releases.  
Maintenance releases will only be published if they contain new fixes.
          <ul>
            <li>
Friday, September 24, 2010 - ATL 3.1.1 maintenance release for Helios Service Release 1.
            </li>
            <li>
Friday, February 25, 2011 - ATL 3.1.2 maintenance release for Helios Service Release 2.
            </li>
            <li>
Version numbers are subject to change should there be be any additional maintenance releases.
            </li>
          </ul> 
        </html:div>
      </postamble>
    </release_milestones>
	<target_environments>
		<html:div>
			In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets
			reasonably
			current versions of the underlying operating environments.
			The ATL
			project depends upon on the Platform and other projects, which
			are
			mostly "pure" Java. The 3.5 release of the Eclipse Platform
			Project
			is written and compiled against version 1.4 of the Java
			Platform
			APIs, and targeted to run on version 1.4 of the Java Runtime
			Environment, Standard Edition. ATL will target the same Java version
			as the platform.
		</html:div>
		<internationalization>
			<html:div>
				The Eclipse Platform is designed as the basis for
				internationalized
				products. The user interface elements provided by
				the Eclipse SDK
				components, including dialogs and error messages, are
				externalized.
				The English strings are provided as the default
				resource bundles. As
				a result, the ATL project will provide English
				strings in its
				default bundles and be localized to a subset of those
				locales
				offered by the Platform. This plan will be updated to
				indicate which
				locales will be provided and the time frame for
				availability.
			</html:div>
		</internationalization>
	</target_environments>
	<compatibility_with_previous_releases>
		<html:div>Most of the 3.1 APIs will be compatible with ATL 3.2.</html:div>
	</compatibility_with_previous_releases>
	<themes_and_priorities>
		<theme name="ATL Editor">
			<description>Improve ATL Editor to improve transformations editing.</description>
			<committed></committed>
			<proposed>
					<html:ul>
						<html:li>ATL code formatter</html:li>
						<html:li>Syntax colors improvement</html:li>
						<html:li>Outline simplification</html:li>
					</html:ul>
			</proposed>
			<deferred></deferred>
		</theme>
		<theme name="ATL Language">
			<description>Make ATL language powerful and easier.</description>
			<committed></committed>
			<proposed>
					<html:ul>
						<html:li>Refining mode improvement: element deletion support, refining on composite models</html:li>
					</html:ul>
			</proposed>
			<deferred></deferred>
		</theme>
	</themes_and_priorities>
	<appendix name="Legal Notices">
		<html:div>
			<ul>
				<li>
					Java is a trademark or a registered trademark of Sun
					Microsystems, Inc.
            </li>
				<li>
					All other products or company names are mentioned for
					identification
					purposes only,
					and may be trademarks or service marks
					of their respective owners.
            </li>
			</ul>
		</html:div>
	</appendix>
</plan>
